{"exam":[{"question":"An organization needs to migrate specialized workloads to the cloud while maintaining their existing complex licensing and architecture. What Google Cloud solution should the organization use?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Compute Engine","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Bare Metal Solution","correct":true,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Cloud Run","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Cloud Function","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"A travel agency wants to seamlessy share their social media content with partners. What should the organization use?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"A NoSQL database","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Anthos Config Management","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"The App Engine standart environment","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"An application programming interface (API)","correct":true,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization wants to transform multiple types of structured and unstructured data in the cloud from various sources. The data must be readily accessible for analysis and insights. Which Cloud data storage system should the organization use?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Relational database","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Private data center","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Data field","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Data warehouse","correct":true,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization wants to use all available data to offer predictive suggestions on their website that improve over time. Which method should the organization use?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Data automation","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Trends analysis","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Machine learning","correct":true,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Multiple regression","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"After rolling out new update, an organization found a minor bug in its online video game. How should the organization approach this bug while following SRE principles?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Accept and learn from the bug because failure is normal","correct":true,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Accept and ignore the bug because it is only minor","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Hold a postmortem to reprimand the employere responsible for the bug","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Document bug correction to eliminate all future bugs","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"Why do organizations often struggle to scale their on-premises application infrastructure?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Scaling compute instances could breach compliance and/or regulation","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Increasing compute capacity is time-consuming and costly","correct":true,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Their serverless compute functions struggle to meet the demand","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Their multi-cloud architecture is complex and expensive","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization wants to use Big Query data analytics to understand their website performance but wants to move only some data into the cloud. Which environment should the organization use?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Private Cloud","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"On-premises","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Multi-Cloud","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Hybrid cloud","correct":true,"why":""}}},{"question":"What is logging within the context of cloud technology?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Writing application and operating system events as text","correct":true,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Monitoring network and resource limitations","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Tracking source code across an organization","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Recording infrastructure and hardware expenditure","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"How does Cloud SQL help organizations create business insights?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Integrates with business intelligence and analytics platforms","correct":true,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Generates predictions using machine learning models","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Generates real-time charts and intelligent analytics","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Transform business data from unstructured to structured","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization recently launched a virtual customer support agent, generating vast amounts of text and speech data. Why should they use a cloud data warehouse to interpret this data?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"To natively visualize both types of data using a dashboard in real time","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"To ingest and analyze structured and unstructured data at scale, in real time","correct":true,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"To secure data transmission between cloud and on-premises environments","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"To transform data from structured to unstructured","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization wants to add a new function to their application. They want to write the code and let the public cloud provider handle the infrastructure. Which infrastructure solution should they use?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Virtual machines","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Bare Metal Solution","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Serverless computing","correct":true,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Container Registry","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization wants to leverage tooling and automation as part of its new DevOps philosophy. Which operational challenge will this resolve?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Repetitive manual tasks that hinder workflows","correct":true,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Time-consuming supervision of creative tasks","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Distribution and supply-chain issues","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Defective technical equipment that limits innovation","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization needs to store structured, semi-structured and unstructured data in its raw, native format in the same repository. Which cloud data management solution should the organization use?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Data field","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Data lake","correct":true,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Database","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Data warehouse","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization  wants its users to validate a series of new features for their app. Why should they use App Engine?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Because their app is containerized and enable by microservices","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Because the updated app will only include new features","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"To run different versions of the app for different users","correct":true,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"To run different versions of the app for the same user","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"How would an organization benefit from using Looker?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Optimal identify and access management","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Leading serverless warehousing technology","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Robust data roll-back accuracy","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Advanced business intelligence and analytic","correct":true,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization delivers a proactive healthcare service. They want to efficiently and automatically collect pacient data. What should the organization encourage the pacients to do?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"User at-home health screening devices and then upload their health data daily","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Wear Internet of Things (IoT) devices that upload their health data in real time","correct":true,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Self-assess their health data and then document and upload it in real time","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Visit a nurse who will use the Internet of Things (IoT) devices to collect and upload their health data","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"How would a global organization benefit frmo managing their data with Cloud Spanner?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Cloud Spanner is optmized for cold storage","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Cloud Spanner replicates data across regions in real time","correct":true,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Cloud Spanner is optmized to ingest unstructured data","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Cloud Spanner visualizes and analyzes data in real time","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"An employee receives an email from their internet service provider asking for their bank account number and password. What cybersecurity threat is this?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Ransomware","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Distributed Denial of Service","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Spamming","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Phishing","correct":true,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization wants to move from a tactical cloud adoption approach to a transformational approach. How should they adapt the way they lead the organization?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Increase top-down visibility and foaster a culture of blamelessness","correct":true,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Shift an operational expenditure model to capital expenditure","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Drive cloud adoption with an individual contributor focus","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Invest in on-premises infrastructure to redesign relationships between IT and employees","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"Why is data stored in Google Cloud secure and private?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Data is encrypted by the Security Command Center","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Data is encrypted by Cloud Data Loss Prevention","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Data is encrypted by default","correct":true,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Data is encrypted when an appropriate tag is applied","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization wants to use multiple marketing datasets to forecast user acquisition. How should they use cloud technology to gain new insights from the data?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Import the datasets into a custom data warehouse, and then archive old data","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Import and selectively archive the datasets in a custom data lake","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Separate the datasets and make predictions using machine learning","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Combine the datasets and make predictins using machine learning","correct":true,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization wants to collect metrics and metadata from their cloud applications and put them into dashboards. Which Google Cloud tool should they use?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Cloud Monitoring","correct":true,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Cloud Trace","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Cloud Logging","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Cloud Debugger","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"A manager wants to review Google Cloud data access among their employees. Who is responsible for defining data access policies?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Cloud Identify","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Google Cloud Customer Care Team","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Their organization's IT team","correct":true,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Their organization's end users","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization has decided to modernize their applications in the cloud to keep up with their customer's needs. What may have prompted this business decision?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Their on-premises applications only autoscale to meet demand","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"They want to change from a pay-as-you-go model to a capital expenditure model","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Their source code changes erroneously without developer interaction","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Their on-premises applications take months to update and deploy","correct":true,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization needs to categorize a large group of photographs using pre-trained machine learning. Which Google Cloud product or service should the organization use?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Vision API","correct":true,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"BigQuery ML","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"AutoML Vision","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Looker","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization provides a loyalty program for its customers. It recently partnered with other businesses so that customers can get loyalty points at a range of other stores. Why should the organization use application programming interfaces (APIs)?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"To migrate all partner data for disaster recovery","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"To analyze and publish loyalty program statistics to a dashboard","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"To personalize recommendations for loyalty card users","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"To connect third-party systems to ensure up-to-date information","correct":true,"why":""}}},{"question":"How do out-of-box APIs make artificial intelligence and machine learning more accessible for all Google Cloud customers?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"They don't require technical specialists","correct":true,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"They don't require data input and validation","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"They require fewer security permissions","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"They all require custom training models","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization finds that the amount of cash in their vending machines doesn't match the value ot items sold. They have decided to upgrade their vending machines with cloud-based mobile payment systems. How Could the organization benefit from this upgrade?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"They could relax data access permissions","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"They could reduce their error budget overspend","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"They could improve their perimeter security","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"They could view data history to see transactions","correct":true,"why":""}}},{"question":"A food delivery service needs access to real-time menu information from all partner restaurants. They also need to share customer order information with the restaurants in real-time. What should the organization use?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Site realiability engineering (SRE)","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"An application programming interface (API)","correct":true,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"A customized machine-learning model","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"A multi-regional database","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization is planning to create may new applications and needs a system for managing and orchestrating their containers. Why should they use Google Kubernets Engine?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"It enables rapid application deployment and testing","correct":true,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"It optmizes virtual machine performance","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"It connects legacy systems to an application","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"It provides pre-written source code for application development","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"Your organization has customer data on-premise but wants to take advantage of the cloud’s storage security and durability. The data contains Personally Identifiable Information (PII) and the organization wants to ensure PIIs are de-identified via masking to keep this information safe. What service would offer this protection?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"BeyondCorp","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"HIPAA Compliance Program","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Cloud Storage","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Cloud Data Loss Prevention","correct":true,"why":"Cloud Data Loss Prevention allows you to protect sensitive data as you migrate to the cloud, it unblocks more workloads as you migrate to the cloud. Cloud DLP enables you to inspect and classify your sensitive data in structured and unstructured workloads. De-identification techniques like tokenization (pseudonymization) let you preserve the utility of your data for joining or analytics while reducing the risk of handling the data by obfuscating the raw sensitive identifiers."}}},{"question":"Employees of your firm pay for GCP projects with personal credit cards, which are refunded at the end of each month by the finance department. Your management team has made the decision to merge all projects under a single billing account. Which of the following approaches is the best solution?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Navigate to the Resource Manage section of the GCP Console and move all projects to the root Organization.","correct":true,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"No change is needed, this method is the best approach","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Create a new billing account and link all the projects together","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Create a support ticket with Google Support to handle the credit card information","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"Your organization has migrated a workload from their on-premises environment to Google Cloud Compute Engine. They have been running the workload for nine months and there has been no change in capacity usage and the capacity is unlikely to increase for the foreseeable future. What would be the cheapest pricing solution?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Committed use discounts","correct":true,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"On-demand pricing","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Sustained use discounts","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Preemptive VMs","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"You are a mobile gaming company that is currently building a mobile gaming application. You need to store 3KB of unnested structured data that represents a player’s profile. This data is real-time and is frequently accessed. Which storage solution will meet this requirement?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"BigQuery","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Cloud Storage","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Cloud BigTable","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Firestore","correct":true,"why":""}}},{"question":"Your organization has virtual machines running on-premise that they want to migrate to the cloud. During the migration process, they would like to also containerize their workloads. Which of the following choices would be suited for this migration?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Database Migration Service","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Migrate for Anthos","correct":true,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Cloud Sprint","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Migrate for Compute Engine","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"You are the team leader assigned to the development of an application. You must optimize the efficient workflow of multiple developers working on the development project while ensuring great flexibility for the entire process. Which of the following cloud computing services is best suited for the task?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Software as a Service (SaaS)","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Platform as a Service (PaaS)","correct":true,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS)","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Function as a Service (FaaS)","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"You've been given the responsibility of managing your department's APIs and establishing security policies for identity verification, authentication, and access control. Which Google Cloud service is the best fit to accomplish this task?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Apigee","correct":true,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"BigQuery","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Google Kubernetes Engine","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Cloud Functions","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization is reviewing its monthly operational expenditure on the Google Cloud platform and breaking down spending per region. Which built-in cloud billing report would be ideal for visualization regional spending?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Cost Table Reports","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Billing Reports","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Cost Breakdown Report","correct":true,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Committed use discounts reports","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"A company is currently developing an application that will run on Google Cloud. They want to ensure that if the application has any issues, it will be tolerant of any downtime. What is the described requirement?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Resiliency","correct":true,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Orchestration","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Dataflow","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Redundancy","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"Which of the following are advantages of adopting a cloud service such as Google Cloud Platform? (Choose 3)","multichoice":true,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Near-unlimited scalability","correct":true,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Utilization of Low-Cost Services","correct":true,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"High reliability","correct":true,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Every service is supported by Open APIs","correct":false,"why":""},"E":{"answer":"The services are completely managed","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"Your organization has collected a large amount of scientific data on mollusk breeding cycles, which the scientific community has requested that you make available for download. Your organization is willing to share this scientific data as long as it does not incur any egress costs when downloaded. Which cloud service will meet this requirement?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Cloud Storage Nearline Storage","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Cloud Storage Requester Pays","correct":true,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Cloud Storage Coldline Storage","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Cloud Storage Signed URLs","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"Your startup is a social trading platform that brokers used items between buyers and sellers. The platform could be described as yard-sale as a service. The platform allows buyers to take a picture of single items or a group of items and will categorize these products. Which of the following solutions would be ideal for the categorization of products?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"AI Platform","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"TensorFlow","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Vertex AI","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Vision AI","correct":true,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization is migrating to Google Cloud and has a legacy PHP application running on Windows 2012 server. This legacy application is designed for internal business purposes and is not heavily used but cannot be eliminated due to its critical business function. The organization wants to eliminate the cost for a Windows License and ideally have a near-zero cost while also being as fully managed as possible. Which computing service would be most ideal for their use case?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Cloud Functions","correct":true,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Cloud Run","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Compute Engine","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Google Kubernetes Engines (GKE)","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization is using Google Cloud and needs to add a person from accounting to be able to download all possible invoices for year-end tax purposes. Which billing feature is the company using in order to provide the needed functionality?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Business Payments Profile","correct":true,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Invoiced Cloud Billing Account","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Self-Service Cloud Billing Account","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Individual Payments Profile","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"A company is architecting an application and wants to save on purchasing new machines, having underutilized machines, and planning for capacity. They do not want to purchase hardware or software and the service provider must provide the maintenance. The method must be cost-effective. Which of the following choices would meet this requirement?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Private cloud","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Public cloud","correct":true,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Microservices","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Containers","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization has migrated their on-premise business-critical workload to Compute Engine. Every time they roll out a deployment, they have to wait for a Virtual Machine’s OS to boot up. The organization needs to reduce this boot time to be the minimal time as possible. Which cloud service will meet their requirements?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Google Kubernetes Engine","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Cloud Functions","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Cloud Run","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Container Optimized OS","correct":true,"why":""},"E":{"answer":"App Engine","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"A VP of a large enterprise is trying to convince the executives of the cost-saving benefits of moving their on-premise workloads to the cloud. Which of the following are characteristics of OPEX? (Choose 2)","multichoice":true,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"You pay based on usage","correct":true,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"You can stop paying for on-premise licenses","correct":true,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"You pay a single time cost for hardware","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"The cloud service provider is responsible for everything","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"You are the team leader of a development project. A new recruit joins and requires the role of a user that spans across multiple projects. Which level of Google resource hierarchy should you assign that role in?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Folder","correct":true,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Project","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Organization","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Resource","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"Your company wants to manage its applications by running containers and other workloads consistently across on-premise data centers and multiple public clouds. Which Google Cloud Service will help you achieve this goal?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Anthos","correct":true,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Transfer Appliance Service","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Compute Engine","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Cloud VPN","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"Your organization is a mobile gaming company and you are creating a follow-up to your popular game Snappy Fish. The development team wants to avoid the scaling issues they experienced with the original title but they also want to continue using an SQL-like database to ensure they can deliver the second title within the next quarter globally. The planned marketing push estimated the reads and write may exceed 100,000 per second. Which database solution would be best suited for their use case?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Firestore","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Cloud Spanner","correct":true,"why":"Cloud Spanner is a fully managed relational database with unlimited scale, strong consistency, and up to 99.999% availability for multi-regional instances. Spanner never needs to be paused for patches, backups, failovers, or even schema updates. Cloud Spanner optimizes performance by automatically sharding the data based on request load and size of the data. As a result, you can spend less time worrying about how to scale your database and instead focus on scaling your business making it an excellent solution for scaling issues while continuing to use a company's SQL-like database."},"C":{"answer":"Cloud SQL","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"BigQuery","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization has large amounts of data residing on Amazon S3 and they want to migrate that data into Google Cloud so they can visualization it using Looker. What Google Cloud service will be meet their requirement?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"BigQuery","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Cloud Storage","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Transfer Appliance Service","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Storage Transfer Service","correct":true,"why":"Storage Transfer Service allows you to quickly import online data into Cloud Storage. You can also set up a repeating schedule for transferring data, as well as transfer data within Cloud Storage, from one bucket to another. Transferring data from Amazon S3 to Cloud Storage using VPC Service Controls and Storage Transfer Service: Configure AWS access, Create VPC Service Controls perimeter, Create an access policy and access level by using Access Context Manager, Use Storage Transfer Service to move data between Amazon S3 and Cloud Storage, Schedule Storage Transfer Service to retrieve data on a schedule."}}},{"question":"You have built a continuous delivery pipeline that will produce a container image for the latest version of your web application. You need to store this image within Google Cloud and it must support multi-regional or regional repositories. Which service would you use?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Containers on Compute Engine","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Artifact Registry","correct":true,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Container Registry","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Cloud Storage","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"Your organization is considering adopting cloud service but there is concern about Google Cloud meeting regulatory compliance. You need to download audit documents performed by third-party providers to prove to key stakeholders. Which choice will satisfy this requirement?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Compliance Reports Manager","correct":true,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Security Command Center","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Assured Workloads","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"BeyondCorp","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"Your organization has asked you to ensure that any current and future Virtual Machine has no external internet access. When configuring your organization policy, how do you need to configure it to meet this requirement?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Apply to the Root Node","correct":true,"why":"An Organization is the root node of the Google Cloud hierarchy of resources. When you apply the Root Node to the organization policy, you can define settings, permissions, and policies for all projects, folders, resources, and Cloud Billing accounts it parents, etc to ensure that any current or future Virtual Machine has no external internet access. You can set an IAM policy at the organization level, the folder level, the project level, or (in some cases) the resource level. Resources inherit the policies of the parent node. If you set a policy at the Organization level, it is inherited by all its child folders and projects, and if you set a policy at the project level, it is inherited by all its child resources."},"B":{"answer":"Apply to all Cloud Compute instances","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Apply to all Projects","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Apply to all Folders","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"You are migrating virtual machines from your on-premise environment to Google Cloud. In case of failure, you want to be able to experiment and try the migrated VMs before putting them in production. Which option will meet this requirement?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Migrate for Anthos","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Cloud Run","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Migrate for Compute Engine Test Clones","correct":true,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Migration waves Runbook","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"A business is considering using cloud computing services to leverage its sales. The business wants to utilize an application managed by a third-party provider so they don't have to worry about server configurations and manual updates. Which of the following cloud computing service is best suited in this scenario?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Platform as a Service (PaaS)","correct":true,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Function as a Service (FaaS)","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Infrastructure as a Service (IaaS)","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Software as a Service (SaaS)","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"Your organization has a large amount of sensitive data they want to analyze using cloud services. They are looking for a cloud networking solution to establish a secure connection to their Virtual Private Cloud(VPC). The method must be cost-effective, and the connection does not require low latency and high availability. What cloud networking solution will meet the requirements to establish a secure connection to their Virtual Private Cloud(VPC)?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Cloud VPN","correct":true,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Partner Interconnect","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Anthos","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Dedicated Interconnect","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"Which of the following is the cloud service provider responsible for based on the shared responsibility model? (Choose 2)","multichoice":true,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Physical datacenter","correct":true,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Hardware patching","correct":true,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Application patching","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Infrastructure architecture","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"Your company has three GCP projects. You have been tasked to ensure they all share policies. Which of the following methods would provide the least amount of error when setting this up?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Create a policy for each individual project","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Add all three projects into a project, and define the policies on the resources","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Add all three projects into a folder, and define the policies on the folder","correct":true,"why":"Folders are a grouping mechanism and can contain projects, other folders, or a combination of both. Folders can be used to group resources that share common IAM policies."},"D":{"answer":"Add all three projects into a resource, and define the policies on the resources","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"You are a mobile gaming company and you need to process real-time game metrics to be analyzed for business intelligence. The metrics of logs are stored in Cloud Storage buckets collected from Cloud Logging. You want a service that can process the data so it can be analyzed in BigQuery. Which service is best suited to process the logs and generate aggregate metrics to be analyzed?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Cloud SQL","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Dataprep","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"DataProc","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Dataflow","correct":true,"why":""}}},{"question":"You have multiple Virtual Machines residing in a resource group. The resources need permission to access BigQuery. How can we grant permissions to the resources to access BigQuery?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Create a Service Account and grant the permissions to the resources (e.g. VMs)","correct":true,"why":"The approach is to create a Service Account and grant it the permissions the resources (e g. the VMs) need. Then you create the VMs to use the Service Account as their identity. Resources have a single identity, usually a Service Account. You should create Service Accounts for each functionally|security equivalent resource. Identities are bound to one or more roles. Roles correspond to one of our more service|API methods. Try to use predefined roles but you can create custom roles."},"B":{"answer":"Create a resource group and add the VMs","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Create Compute Engine resource","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Add the BigQuery policy","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"A company is working on a project that requires the ingestion of user interaction from end-user apps and server events from many clients simultaneously. Which service best fits the requirement?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Dataflow","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Firestore","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Pub/Sub","correct":true,"why":"Ingestion user interaction and server events: To make use of user interaction events from end-user apps or server events from your system, you may forward them to Pub/Sub and then use a stream processing tool such as Dataflow, which delivers them to BigQuery, Bigtable, Cloud Storage and other databases. Pub/Sub allows you to gather events from many clients simultaneously. Therefore, Pub/Sub is the correct choice among others."},"D":{"answer":"Firebase","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"What security principle does an organization gain upon utilizing Identity and Access Management (IAM)?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Integrity","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Availability","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Confidentiality","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Least Privilege","correct":true,"why":""}}},{"question":"Which Google cloud offering is best suitable for Apache Spark and Presto solutions?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Cloud Run","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Google Kubernetes Engine","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Dataproc","correct":true,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Dataprep","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"You are developing a new social platform on a custom Linux container. The web application is currently in private beta and you need to quickly iterate on features, so deployment is frequent. The private beta userbase is globally distributed so the app will be in use 24 hours. You want the service to be fully managed. Which two services are viable options for completing this task? (Choose 2)","multichoice":true,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"App Engine Standard","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Google Kubernetes Engine","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"App Engine Flexible","correct":true,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Cloud Run","correct":true,"why":""},"E":{"answer":"Cloud Run for Anthos","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"Your organization has virtual machines running on-premise that they want to migrate to the cloud. Which choice would be suited for this migration?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Migrate for Anthos","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Migration waves","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Migrate for Compute Engine","correct":true,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Google Cloud VMWare Engine","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"You are a developer startup developing a new food delivery service for popular dine-in and fast food restaurants. An important component to the design is having real-time updates reflected as soon as they are added or changed to the database, ensuring that customers and drivers are aware of when food is ready for pickup and when food is in transit to their end destination. Which Google offering best meets these requirements?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Pub/Sub","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Cloud Storage","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Firestore","correct":true,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Dataflow","correct":false,"why":""},"E":{"answer":"Cloud Tasks","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization has a mobile workforce that frequently meets customers at their offices or in public spaces. There is a concern within your organization that internal company data visualizations from Looker should only be accessible from cooperating devices when being accessed within the corporate offices. Which security service allows for limiting access in this scenario?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Cloud Identity","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"IAM","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Organization Policy Service","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"BeyondCorp and Identity-Aware Proxy","correct":true,"why":""}}},{"question":"You have many terabytes of data residing within BigQuery. Your organization has asked you to analyze the data using machine learning. Which choice would be ideal for this scenario?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"DataFusion","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Vertex AI","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Dataproc","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"BigQuery ML","correct":true,"why":"BigQuery ML lets you create and execute machine learning models in BigQuery using standard SQL queries. BigQuery ML democratizes machine learning by letting SQL practitioners build models using existing SQL tools and skills. BigQuery ML increases development speed by eliminating the need to move data."}}},{"question":"A game company is set to release their new sports title next week and it's expected to receive large amounts of traffic for the first quarter. It is important the reads have very low latency. Which data store is ideal for this use case?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Cloud Storage","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Cloud BigTable","correct":true,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Firestore","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"BigQuery","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"Which Google resource hierarchy level is required to use service-level resources such as Compute Engine virtual machines (VMs) and form the basis for enabling services, APIs, and IAM permissions?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Resources","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Organization","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Projects","correct":true,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Folders","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"Your organization has many mobile workforces utilizing corporate devices such as laptops, tablets, and phones to meet customers at their offices or in public spaces. There is concern about the overall security posture and your IT department has asked how we can utilize google cloud to manage these devices remotely using the company on-premise Active Directory server. Which Google Cloud service would be suited for this scenario?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Cloud Identity","correct":true,"why":"Cloud Identity is an Identity as a Service (IDaaS) solution that centrally manages users and groups. You can configure Cloud Identity to federate identities between Google and other identity providers, such as Active Directory and Azure Active Directory. Cloud Identity also gives you more control over the accounts that are used in your organization. For example, if developers in your organization use personal accounts, such as Gmail accounts, those accounts are outside of your control. When you adopt Cloud Identity, you can manage access and compliance across all users in your domain."},"B":{"answer":"Google Cloud Directory Sync","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Managed Microsoft AD","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Identity and Access Management (IAM)","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization has virtual machines running VMware-based applications in their on-premise environment. The organization is planning a lift-and-shift migration to google cloud. Which choice will meet this requirement?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Migrate for Anthos","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Google Cloud VMWare Engine","correct":true,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Migration waves Runbook","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Lift-and-Shift Import Service (LASIS)","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization with a GCP account has 50 TB of data residing on their local storage and they want to quickly transfer the data to Google Cloud for analysis. Which service can the organization use to meet this requirement?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Cloud Storage","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Storage Transfer Service","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Dataproc","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Transfer Appliance Service","correct":true,"why":""}}},{"question":"An organization has an LDAP(Lightweight Directory Access Protocol) server where they want to allow their users to access Google Cloud resources. Whenever an LDAP user is removed, it should also remove access to Google Cloud. Which service will meet this requirement?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Identity-Aware-Proxy","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Cloud Identity","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"BeyondCorp","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Google Cloud Directory Sync","correct":true,"why":""}}},{"question":"You are a developer working for a well-established organization building its first Business-to-consumer(B2C) web application. There is uncertainty about the popularity of this new web application. You have been asked to make sure the operational costs can scale to zero. Which two Google offerings are viable options to meet the requirements? (choose 2)","multichoice":true,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Dataproc","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Firebase","correct":true,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Pub/Sub","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Cloud Run","correct":true,"why":""}}},{"question":"Your organization is utilizing an open-source distrusted computing workload on Compute Engine and they want to ensure high availability but there is a requirement latency of around 10ms. Which of the following availability architectures is best suited for this scenario?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Multiple regions, multiple zones","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Multiple regions, single zone","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"One region, multiple zones","correct":true,"why":"To ensure high availability and to handling failures, you should distribute your resources across multiple zones and regions to tolerate outages. To decrease network latency, you might want to choose a region or zone that is close to your point of service. For example, if you mostly have customers on the East Coast of the US, then you might want to choose a primary region and zone that is close to that area and a backup region and zone that is also close by."},"D":{"answer":"Single Region, single zone","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"You have been tasked to transfer on-premises data from your network to your Virtual Private Cloud (VPC) networks in Google Cloud. The method of transfer requires that you fully control the interconnect, high availability, and a 10 Gbps pipe. Cost is not a factor. Which of the following methods fulfills the requirement?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Cloud VPN","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Cloud Dedicated Interconnect","correct":true,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Cloud Partner Interconnect","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Direct Peering","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"Your organization is planning a migration to Google Cloud. Your organization is composed of multiple departments, and each department has various workloads they want to self-govern within Google Cloud. Which is the ideal organizational structure?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Create a project per department, create a folder per workload","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Create a folder per department, create a project per workload","correct":true,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"Create a google form, when a department request is made create a project per workload","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Create a project in the root node for per workload","correct":false,"why":""}}},{"question":"Your organization offers a data visualization service where users can upload multiple archives containing spreadsheets. You need to generate and email a service agreement PDF report for a customer using a data processing job that takes on average 1 hour to process and no longer than five hours (one-time use). What would be the cheapest computing solution?","multichoice":false,"alternatives":{"A":{"answer":"Committed use discounts","correct":false,"why":""},"B":{"answer":"Sustained use discounts","correct":false,"why":""},"C":{"answer":"On-demand pricing","correct":false,"why":""},"D":{"answer":"Preemptible Virtual Machines","correct":true,"why":""}}}]}